

Contact

Phone

+49 163 514 8635

Email

casamitjana.julia@gmail.com

Address

Dahlmanstr. 6, 10629, Berlin

Birth date

03/01/1990

Tools and skills

- HTML5 and Sass
- Javascript and Typescript
- React
- Git
- UI/UX
- Figma

Languages

English (Advanced)

German (Intermediate)

Catalan and Spanish (Native)

Julia Casamitjana

Frontend developer

Bringing three years of software development experience, I've gained expertise primarily in frontend technologies including HTML5, Sass, Javascript, Typescript, ViewComponent and in other tools such as Git, Youtrack or Figma. Complementing my technical skills, I hold a PSM 1 Scrum certification and a background in product design that enhances my ability to create compelling UI/UX. I now aspire to further my professional journey as a React developer, building upon the foundation laid by several personal projects that you will find in my portfolio.

Experience

Oct. 2020 - Present

Hasso Plattner Institut für Digital Engineering gGmbH | 14480 Potsdam

Software Developer

Building and maintaining the <u>openHPI</u> platform, with special focus on the frontend development. Creating a design system and enlarging the library of UI components. Tools and technologies: Javascript, HTML5, Sass, rails, Stencil.js, Typescript, git, and Youtrack. Working with Scrum methodology.

Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2019

Dassault Systemes Deutschland GmbH | 81829 München

Technical Sales Specialist

Provide technical sales support for SOLIDWORKS products as part of the technical team responsible in Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and Poland. Preparation, support and implementation of product presentations, webinar series, as well as training of regional sales partners.

Aug. 2015 - Mar. 2016

KONUX GmbH | 81369 München

Product Engineer

Execution of hazard analysis, FMEA and documentation of development processes. . Establishing 3D Data and drawings using SOLIDWORS. Testing design concepts concerning the implementation of a torque sensor.

Education

Sept 2013 - Sept 2014

Université de Lorraine - ENSGSI | 90647 Nancy, France

Master's in Innovation Management and Industrial Design

Principal subjects covered: Technical Creativity for Product Conception, Innovation Marketing, Need Analysis, Value Engineering and Project Management.

Sept 2008 - June 2013

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya -ETSEIB | 08028 Barcelona, Spain

Master's degree in Industrial Engineering

Principal subjects covered: Calculus, Algebra, Physics, Computing and Programming, Materials Science, Thermodynamics, Mechanics, Fluid Dynamics, Electronic Circuits, Heat and Mass Transfer, Automatic Control, Theory of Structures, Industrial Organization and Business Administration.